<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Discovering The Goodness In Data</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Discovering The Goodness In Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rstudio on AWS - How can it be so simple?</title>
      <link>/post/rstudio-on-aws-how-can-it-be-so-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rstudio-on-aws-how-can-it-be-so-simple/</guid>
      <description>Rstudio on AWS In this post, we’ll look at the steps involved in bringing up Rstudio in AWS environment based on Amazon Machine Images (AMI).
You won’t believe, it is so simple. First, login to AWS Management Console. Click on EC2 Service. On the left pane, select AMIs. You can search for pre built images here. Search for ‘rstudio’. You’ll see something very similar to the below image.
Select the image and click launch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Deep Dive in to CMPD Traffic Stops</title>
      <link>/post/a-deep-dive-in-to-cmpd-traffic-stops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-deep-dive-in-to-cmpd-traffic-stops/</guid>
      <description>Analyzing Charlotte-Mecklenburg Police Department Traffic Stops In this post, we’ll examine a data set of stops by the Charlotte-Mecklenburg Police Department (CMPD).
Our focus will be to understand what factors are related to whether someone is searched or not for a traffic stop.
# Loading the libraries library(dplyr) library(tidyverse) library(scales) library(ggspatial) library(ggplot2) library(stringr) library(lubridate) library(sf) library(viridis) library(ggridges) library(gapminder) library(forcats) library(plotly) df &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;Officer_Traffic_Stops.csv&amp;quot;) Demographics of drivers First, look at the data using the glimpse() function from dplyr</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Data - An art rather than a science</title>
      <link>/post/visualizing-data-an-art-rather-than-a-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/visualizing-data-an-art-rather-than-a-science/</guid>
      <description> Contents will be added soon…  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB on its home stretch to become ACID compliant</title>
      <link>/post/mongodb-on-its-home-stretch-to-become-acid-compliant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mongodb-on-its-home-stretch-to-become-acid-compliant/</guid>
      <description>The product was on its home stretch to become ACID compliant when they announced the new features of MongoDB 4.0 at MongoDB World 18 summit. In other words, one of the most popular NoSQL database is making the life of developers, architects, application owners and other stakeholders a lot easier by bringing in multi document transactional capability. This will make MongoDB stand out among the NoSQL clan and bridges a major gap between noSQL and traditional databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration of Mainframe Batch Workloads to ETL Platforms</title>
      <link>/post/migration-of-batch-workloads-to-etl-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/migration-of-batch-workloads-to-etl-platforms/</guid>
      <description>During the late nineties, technology pundits predicted the imminent downfall of the mainframes. These ginormous computing machines from an earlier age seemed to have outlived their usefulness. Now, two decades later, the Big Iron continues to rule the roost running inside some of the world’s biggest companies including banks, retailers, insurance companies and airlines. 92 of the top 100 banks worldwide, 70% of the world’s largest retailers, 10 out of 10 of the world’s largest insurers and 23 of the world’s 25 largest airlines run on mainframes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Ramkumar Nottath</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>About me A senior technology architect who started the career on Mainframes and extended his horizons to Traditional, NoSQL, NewSQL databases and BigData technologies and Data Science. It might be just a coincidence that both my parents are teachers and I started my career with Infosys back in 2004 as an educator. For the last one and half decade I have been working on several data migration / analytics initiatives across financial clients.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>